<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R Project on Biocozy.net</title>
    <link>https://biocozy.net/tags/r-project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R Project on Biocozy.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright Biocozy.net</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2009 13:56:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://biocozy.net/tags/r-project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>parallel computation using the caret package</title>
      <link>https://biocozy.net/posts/2009-10-05-parallel-computation-using-the-caret-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2009 13:56:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://biocozy.net/posts/2009-10-05-parallel-computation-using-the-caret-package/</guid>
      <description>Library caret is a wonderful R package for tuning a variety of machine learning classification and regression algorithms. But it can take a long time to run, since model tuning usually involves running multiple bootstrapped replicates for each point in your tuning grid.
If you have a multi-core desktop machine, you can speed up your calls to the caret function train by using explicit parallelism.
There were just a couple hitches to get it flying on my 64bit quad core Optiplex 960 running linux kernel 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another workaround for Memory Issues in R / Bioconductor</title>
      <link>https://biocozy.net/posts/2009-04-15-another-workaround-for-memory-issues-in-r-bioconductor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2009 11:35:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://biocozy.net/posts/2009-04-15-another-workaround-for-memory-issues-in-r-bioconductor/</guid>
      <description>This post could be entitled &amp;ldquo;Error: cannot allocate vector of size 256.0 Mb&amp;rdquo;. R provides this maddening response for even the most trivial seeming tasks. I have a 4 Gb linux system, and I have encountered this error message for &amp;ldquo;vector of size&amp;rdquo; in the 10s of Mb. And system wide, there appears to be plenty of memory still available, and the swap space hasn&amp;rsquo;t been touched.
What&amp;rsquo;s going on with R memory management?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Girke R Bioconductor manual</title>
      <link>https://biocozy.net/posts/2009-04-09-the-girke-r-bioconductor-manual/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2009 16:29:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://biocozy.net/posts/2009-04-09-the-girke-r-bioconductor-manual/</guid>
      <description>I came across Thomas Girke&amp;rsquo;s wonderful R/Bioconductor manual today. If I had had this UC Riverside professors notes when I started, I would have saved a lot of time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R variable class (data types)</title>
      <link>https://biocozy.net/posts/2009-03-25-r-variable-class-data-types/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2009 14:06:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://biocozy.net/posts/2009-03-25-r-variable-class-data-types/</guid>
      <description>R does some amazing things, and often seems to know just want you want to do. Data type &amp;ldquo;coercion&amp;rdquo; can also backfire.
I just discovered a great way to check to see how R has interpreted the columns of a file you have just loaded.
&amp;gt; sapply(dataframeobject, class)
gender type score
&amp;ldquo;factor&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;factor&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;numeric&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating BioMart queries into BioConductor with the biomaRt package</title>
      <link>https://biocozy.net/posts/2009-03-25-integrating-biomart-queries-into-bioconductor-with-the-biomart-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2009 10:33:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://biocozy.net/posts/2009-03-25-integrating-biomart-queries-into-bioconductor-with-the-biomart-package/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just realized the considerable power and convenience of a web-based bioinformatic resource I have overlooked in the past: biomart.org.
What gets my attention now is the ability to integrate BioMart queries right into your BioConductor pipeline, with a package called biomaRt
The Seattle 2009 BioConductor workshop looks like it was great &amp;ndash; sadly, I missed it. But you can still access some presentation materials on biomaRt.
Installation of biomaRt is accomplished like any other BioConductor pacakge:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pulling data from GEO into R Bioconductor expression sets (eSet)</title>
      <link>https://biocozy.net/posts/2009-03-19-pulling-data-from-geo-into-r-bioconductor-expression-sets-eset/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2009 16:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://biocozy.net/posts/2009-03-19-pulling-data-from-geo-into-r-bioconductor-expression-sets-eset/</guid>
      <description>I just discovered how easy Bioconductor makes it to import data from the Gene Expression Omnibus (GEO).
First, be sure you have the GEOquery package from Bioconductor. You will probably need to install the curl4 devel library package using apt-get or whatever you use to do such things. On my Ubuntu 8.10 distro, the requisite package is called libcurl4-gnutls-dev. After you have this, you should be able to install GEOquery like any other Bioconductor package, ie:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classification and regression trees (CART)</title>
      <link>https://biocozy.net/posts/2009-03-19-classification-and-regression-trees-cart/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2009 10:14:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://biocozy.net/posts/2009-03-19-classification-and-regression-trees-cart/</guid>
      <description>Just about the take the plunge into various machine learning analyses, starting with some simple classification and regression trees (CART) to try to model patient outcomes based on clinical observations. I&amp;rsquo;ll be mainly focusing on classification.
In gearing up for this, I just found an amazing resource, this guide to machine learning R packages, maintained by Torsten Hothorn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get the BioConductor packages to install correctly in Ubuntu 8.10</title>
      <link>https://biocozy.net/posts/2008-12-15-how-to-get-the-bioconductor-packages-to-install-correctly-in-ubuntu-8-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2008 11:15:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://biocozy.net/posts/2008-12-15-how-to-get-the-bioconductor-packages-to-install-correctly-in-ubuntu-8-10/</guid>
      <description>Apparently, the repositories for the 8.10 (Intrepid Ibex) release of Ubuntu do not completely specify all of the dependencies for the R-base synaptic package.
I could not get various packages to compile, until I installed
sudo apt-get install libxml2-dev libatlas-base-dev
This solved many build problems, including package XML, but I was still getting the following error when attempting to load library vsn:

 &amp;gt; library(vsn)
Loading required package: lattice</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>